<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN"
"technicalContent/dtd/topic.dtd" [
<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->
<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->
]>
<topic id="4d_Intro_1">
  <title>4D Pubs: Distributed Dynamic Document Display</title>

  <body>
    <p>4D Pubs is a single-page web application that transforms DITA source
    into HTML, on the fly (per request). The transforms execute in the
    browser, using the browser's XSLT processor. This provides benefits, and
    it also imposes some limitations.</p>

    <section><title>Benefits</title><p><ul>
        <li><p>Agile work flow -- No need to generate HTML for each pubs
        cycle.</p></li>

        <li><p>Single skin -- Edit look and feel via a single page.</p></li>

        <li><p>Dynamic in the Browser -- The client can intervene in the
        transform at the last minute. For example, the client can filter
        content according to user role, or the client can execute a process to
        generate/retrieve real-time data.</p></li>

        <li><p>Distributed Source -- When cross-domain requests are enabled
        (either through CGI or Servlets), 4D can load distributed content and
        stitch this content into a single body.</p></li>
      </ul></p></section>

    <section><title>Limitations</title><ul>
        <li><p>In-Memory Transforms -- Because transforms are in memory,
        performance is affected by topic size (in theory). This problem
        reduced by the fact that DITA topics are meant to be smaller than a
        full document. Note that chapters in the Project Gutenberg publication
        of the Outline of Science are fairly large, and 4D doesn't show
        noticeable degradation when loading these topics.</p></li>

        <li><p>In-Memory Search -- This implementation loads search data into
        memory, and performs search in the client. There's a theoretical limit
        to the number of topics this can handle. Note that you could implement
        a search service that uses data stored on the server. This
        implementation executes search in the browser to support a specific
        use case. Note that we support over 300 topics, and search does not pose a problem.</p></li>

        <li><p>Limited Support of DITA -- This implementation does not support
        all of DITA. We created this to support specific business needs
        (primarily online help), and we have no case for supporting all of
        DITA. Additional support will require a combination of XSLT,
        Javascript, and CSS development</p></li>

        <li><p>XSLT 1.0 -- In-browser transforms means that 4D is restricted
        to XSLT 1.0</p></li>
      </ul></section>

    <p>Of course, there are other benefits and limitations. By illustrating
    the most obvious candidates, these lists can help you understand how 4D
    works.</p>

    <p>This repository includes an AngularJS implementation of 4D Pubs. We
    ported to AngularJS to enable pulling a subset of the 4D services into a
    product GUI that is also implemented in AngularJS. In this way, we can
    integrate DITA in the product user interface. </p>
  </body>
</topic>
